# Nguyen Thi Chi Lam

**DATA ANALYST** 



**Date of birth** 15/10/2001

**Gender** Female

**Address**District 5, Ho Chi Minh City

Phone 0967423249

Email nguyenlam151001@gmail.com

**Website** linkedin.com/in/lâm-nguyễn-a42b31286

## **Objective**

Apply data analysis and visualization skills to provide insights to support business strategy and optimize operations. Proficient in Excel, Power BI and have a background in SQL, Python. Desire to learn, develop expertise and contribute to performance monitoring, trend detection, and make improvement recommendations to drive business growth.

## **Skills**

- Data Analysis and Visualization: PowerBI, Excel
- Programming: Python, SQL
- Project Management: Jira, Trello
- Stakeholder Engagement & Communication
- Soft Skills: Analytical Thinking, Problem-Solving, Communication and Collaboration

## **Activities**

June 2020 - Sep 2020

Manga Trans & Edit Team

Volunteer Translator

May 2020 - Jun 2020

#### **UIT SAFE Volunteer**

Participate in the volunteer movement to measure the temperature of students, lecturers and visitors to UIT during the Covid19 outbreak.

Dec 2019

### **UIT ENGLISH SPEAKING CONTEST**

Participate in the English contest about the era of technological development.

## Certifications

TOEIC Certificate (Score 835) | 2024

# **Experience**

Dec 2024 - Present

#### FREELANCE RESEARCH ANALYST

- Collect and research scientific articles related to Quality of Accounting Information Systems (QAIS).
- Analyze survey data using SPSS, perform Exploratory Factor Analysis (EFA) and calculate Cronbach's Alpha to test the reliability of the data.
- Support research for thesis on QAIS in enterprise.

Sep 2023 - Dec 2023

#### **CJ OLIVENETWORKS VINA**

**BUSINESS ANALYST & QA TESTER INTERN** 

#### **Business Analyst:**

- Analyzed As-is business processes and suggested improvements.
- Designed a user-friendly contract management screen.
- Defined business requirements and documented workflows using Jira/Confluence.

#### **QA Tester:**

- Developed test cases and conducted functional testing.
- Reported and tracked software defects in Jira, collaborating with developers to improve product quality.

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

#### **CAT MARKET RESEARCH & ADVISOR**

- Researched and observed market trends, breed popularity, and buyer preferences.
- Evaluate regional prices and demand based on experience and observations.
- Advise customers on appropriate breed selection and basic care.
- Negotiate reasonable prices between buyers and sellers.

#### **Education**

Oct 2019 - Nov 2024

# UNIVERSITY OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY - UIT

#### **Major: Information System**

- Relevant coursework: System Analysis & Design; Data, Process, and Object Modeling; Enterprise Resource Planning
- Graduation Project: Forecasting gold price based on machine learning.